Inventory of the George F. Koether papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1928-1988
  - Spiritual Mobilization, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 16: 23)
    Includes correspondence with William Johnson, editor of the publication, Faith and Freedom published by Spiritual Mobilization.
  - T, 1956-1987 (Box-folder 16: 24)
    Correspondents include Kenneth Templeton and Neil J. Thomas.
  - University of Michigan, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 16: 25)
  - University of Oregon, 1979 (Box-folder 16: 26)
  - van Notten, Michael, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 16: 27)
    General note
    Variant spellings: van Notten, Michiel and van Notten, Micheal
  - Wabash College (seminars), 1970-1978 (Box-folder 16: 28)
  - Wallace, Mike (Box-folder 16: 29)
  - Wortham, Anne, 1968-1988 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
  - Wright, E. A., 1981-1982 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - von Mises family file and the Mises Institute, 1948-1988
    - von Mises notes, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - von Mises, Ludwig, circa 1948-1982 (Box-folder 17: 5)
      Correspondence and writings by Ludwig von Mises, including a typescripted essay "The Republican Platform" with an annotation on the cover sheet by Koether: "date uncertain probably circa 1948 - 1960?".
    - von Mises, Ludwig--anniversary celebrations, 1954-1988 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - von Mises, Ludwig--obituaries, 1959-1985 (Box-folder 17: 7)
      Includes correspondence with Bruno Leoni and Llewellyn Rockwell, Jr.
    - von Mises, Margit, 1948-1988 (Box-folder 17: 8-10)
    - The Mises Institute, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 17: 11)
- Speeches and Writings, 1930-2003
  Speeches and writings by George Koether. Includes research materials such as clippings, notes, and correspondence.
  - Biographical materials, circa 1973-1980 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - "Adventures in Human Action" material, circa 1972 (Box-folder 18: 2-3)
    Brochure produced by editor George Koether under B.G. Koether Associates. The board of consulting economists for this program included: Henry Hazlitt, Murray N. Rothbard, and Hans Sennholz.
  - Anti-communist activities, clippings, sworn statements, and "The Communist Technique," (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - "The Attack on Profit," drafts and monographs, 1947-2003 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - "The Cayman Dollar and the Cayman Destiny,", 1973-1980 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Communism and socialism writings, 1959 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Continental Can Company pamphlets, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    Includes "The Real Danger in Automation" pamphlet by Ellison L. Hazard (President), ghost written by Koether.
  - Economic education materials, 1930-circa 1983 (Box-folder 18: 9-10)
  - "End of Political Man," outlines, circa 1978 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    Includes outlines and drafts for "The Capitalist at Bay," and "'Natural Law' and 'Natural Man.'"
  - "Free Market and Free Press," lecture,The Freeman articles, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - "Free Markets, Free Banking, and Free People,", undated (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - "The Great Farm Problem," abstract, 1960 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    On William Petersen's "The Great Farm Problem, regarding the United States' historical interventions in the agricultural industry from Il Politico, University of Pavia, 1960.
  - "Janus Journalism: Thoughts on the Pitfalls of 'Middle of the Road,'" (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - "Heilbroner's Fallacies," critique, 1954 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Ingersoll-Rand Corporation, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Look Magazine, 1941-1960
    Telegrams announcing Koether's journalism awards, clippings, photographs, and printed copies of articles. Includes index of articles written for Look Magazine.
    - Articles and reprints, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Photographs and printed matter, 1941-1953 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box-folder 19: 5-6)
    Includes an excerpt from Koether's The Ass that Went to Washington."
  - "'Natural Law' and 'Natural Man,'" typescripts, undated (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - A Primer in Economics, 1957-1977
    - Correspondence (Arlington House Publishers), 1957-1977 (Box-folder 19: 8)
      Includes outlines and notes.
    - Notes for introduction, circa 1971 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Typescript and notes, 1977 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - "The Remedy for Union Officials...,", undated (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - "The Road," research file, circa 1904-1945 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - "Stories by Koether,", 1951-1960 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    Includes ghost-written articles and publications; Look Magazine articles such as "Don't Drive a Death Trap" and "Don't Put a Killer in Your Car;" and articles written for Christian Economics.
  - Warner & Swasey Company advertisements, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    Advertisments on the topics of America and international relations for the Warner & Swasey Company, a machinery company selling machine tools, textile machinery, and heavy equipment. Some advertisements appear in U.S. News & World Report. The "Men 6 Feet Tall Are Too Big" ad is a re-print from April 1951 and August 1957.
  - Speeches, lectures, and press releases, 1934-1979
    - Speech research file, undated (Box-folder 20: 1)
      Includes typescript of "Essay on Money as a Medium of Commerce with Remarks on the Advantages and Disadvantages of Paper Admitted into General Circulation, by a Citizen of the United States," by John Witherspoon.
    - Speech research on inflation, 1931-1981 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - "Business Survival in an Age of Inflation,", 1960-1979 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - CMRE conferences and speaking engagements (Box-folder 20: 4)
      On monetary policy, inflation and sound money.
    - "Free Market and Free Press," lecture, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Wortham, Anne, 1977 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - "Ted V. Rodgers Journalism Award,", 1958 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - United States Steel Corporation speeches and press releases, 1961 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Writings by others, 1954-1978
    - "Economic Myths of Early Capitalism," Hayek, Frederich A., circa 1954 (Box-folder 20: 9)
      Hobhouse Lecture Series includes "The Political Order of a Free Society," by Arthur Shenfield and "Is the Tide Turning?," by Henry Makoud.
    - "Inflation, Liberty, and Monetary Constitutions," Marzano, Antonio, undated (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - "The Philosophical Basis of a Free Society," commentary by Vittorio Mathieu, undated (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - "The Three Sources of Human Value" (The Hobhouse Lecture), Hayek, Friedrich A., 1978 (Box-folder 20: 12)
      Hobhouse Lecture (London School of Economics, May 17, 1978), "The Three Sources of Human Values." Includes, "The Misconception of Human Rights as Positive Claims" (1966) with a clipping on human rights and the Belgian Massacres of 1876.
    - "Voluntary Association and the State," Petro Sylvester, 1962 (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - Mont Pelerin Society file, 1947-1974 (Box-folder 20:14-16/ 21:1)
    - "When Ford Stock Went Begging," Hayes, H.J., undated (Box-folder 21: 2)
- Photographs and Printed Matter, 1903 - 1980s
  - Books donated to the Foundation of Economic Education, copies of title pages, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Photographs, 1903, undated (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Photographs, inflation, 1863-1957 (Box-folder 21: 7)
    Includes images of President Truman, President Eisenhower, Chilean riots, and foreign currency.
  - The Saturday Evening Post articles, 1961 (Box-folder 21: 8)